SUMMARY

MSc Data Science Student at EPFL with 5+ years of experience as a Software Engineer. Previously ML engineer at integrate.ai, co-founder at destin.ai, and Next AI entrepreneur. Actively interested in research into the neurosymbolic AI, reasoning, compositionality, linguistically motivated NLP and knowledge-driven, cognitive-model-based AI.

CONTACT

mismayilza@gmail.com

mete.is

+41765051292

♀ Lausanne, Switzerland

in mismayilzada

mismayil ?

SKILLS

LANGUAGES **TECHNOLOGIES** English (advanced) Python Turkish (native) **Iavascript** Azerbaijani (native) Java Russian (elementary) HTML / CSS French (B1) SOL / NoSOL git / linux node.js / react.js MLOps / DevOps numpy / pandas Tensorflow / Pytorch sklearn / pyspark

PROJECTS

spacy / huggingface

matplotlib / seaborn

Words and Personalities

Data analysis project exploring the relationship between language and personalities

mini-pytorch

From scratch implementation of pytorch autograd and core modules $\,$

Differentially Private Random Forest Algorithm

Contributed to IBM's differential privacy library diffprivlib

EDUCATION

ÉPFL Sep. 2021 - Present

Master Data Science 2023

Bachelor Computer Science 2016

University of Waterloo Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2016

With Distinction

EXPERIENCE

ÉPFL Lausanne, Switzerland

Student Assistant Sep. 2022 - Present

Assisting in grading homeworks and helping students with their projects for graduate course Applied Data Analysis

Research Assistant Nov. 2022 - Present

Research on temporal causal reasoning in NLP at Artificial Intelligence Lab (LIA)

Sony Inc.Tokyo, JapanResearch InternJul. 2022 - Sep. 2022

Research and development of an open-domain dialog system that can mimick

any given character based on few utterances

integrate.aiToronto, CanadaSoftware/ML EngineerJul. 2019 - Aug. 2021

Designed and developed core ML infrastructure and tools to train, test and deploy models
Collaborated with ML Scientists on research projects to incorporate state of the art ML techniques

Designed and developed a Federated Learning framework similar to flower dev

Researched and integrated various Differential Privacy techniques into our ML models

Destin AI Toronto, Canada

Co-founder & CTO Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2019

End-to-end design and development of the core platform (destin.ai)

Built an AI-powered chatbot solution (m.me/heydestin)

Participated in Next AI, DMZ, Legal Innovation Zone and MaRS accelerator programs

Bluecat Networks Toronto, Canada Software Engineer Sep. 2017 - Jul. 2018

Enhanced Bluecat's DNS, DHCP and IP solution with various features

Cisco Systems Ottawa, Canada

Software Engineer Jun. 2016 - Jul. 2017

Developed a Python library for programmatic management of Cisco switches and routers

PUBLICATIONS

kogito: A Commonsense Knowledge Inference Toolkit

Preprin

[Paper] [Code]

AWARDS

Full State Scholarship (2012-2016) Sep. 2012

Government of Azerbaijan

Full funding during study at University of Waterloo

Certificate of Distinction in the Euclid Mathematics Contest Feb. 2012

University of Waterloo

Presidential Scholarship Sep. 2010

Government of Azerbaijan

Awarded to top students entering university studies